<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2020 OSS Lugaru contributors -->
<!-- Originally written by Neal Gompa <ngompa13@gmail.com> -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>lugaru.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+ and CC-BY-SA-3.0</project_license>
  <name>Lugaru HD</name>
  <summary>Third person ninja rabbit fighting game</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Lugaru (pronounced Loo-GAH-roo) is a cross-platform third-person action game.
      The main character, Turner, is an anthropomorphic rebel bunny rabbit with impressive combat skills.
    </p>

    <p>
      In his quest to find those responsible for slaughtering his village,
      he uncovers a far-reaching conspiracy involving the corrupt leaders
      of the rabbit republic and the starving wolves from a nearby den.
      Turner takes it upon himself to fight against their plot and save
      his fellow rabbits from slavery.
    </p>
  </description>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.2" date="2017-02-11">
      <p>
        Second release of the open source Lugaru project! It continues the refactoring
        work to make the old Lugaru code more modular and easier to maintain and
        extend. A particular attention was given to the development tools (in game
        editor) to improve the modability of the game.
      </p>
      <p>Highlights:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Keep track of and display the game's version number in the console and main menu.</li>
        <li>
          Many fixes and improvements to development tools, most of them should now work
          as described in the documentation.
        </li>
        <li>New monospace font for the console, more readable.</li>
        <li>Configurable campaign end message.</li>
        <li>Various fixes to mod levels and campaigns.</li>
        <li>
          A lot of behind-the-scenes refactoring that should help bring more interesting changes
          in future releases.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1" date="2016-12-14">
      <p>
        First release of the open source Lugaru project! It contains most commits
        made from various contributors since the open sourcing in 2010, and is
        therefore more advanced than the preceding Lugaru HD release by Wolfire.
      </p>
      <p>Highlights:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Multiple campaigns support, making it easier to install and play mods!</li>
        <li>
          These Lugaru mods are included by default as alternative to the Turner official campaign:
          <ul>
            <li>Temple, by Silb</li>
            <li>Empire, by Jendraz</li>
            <li>The Seven Tasks, by Philtron R. (albeit with some engine-related issues)</li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>
          All assets (animations, textures, models, maps, sounds, etc.) of Lugaru HD
          by Wolfire are under a free and open source license (CC-BY-SA 3.0)!
        </li>
        <li>
          Window and input management ported from SDL 1.2 to SDL 2.0, improving the
          support for modern screen resolutions and fullscreen mode, as well as
          better input handling.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">mild</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-profanity">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="864" height="417">
        https://osslugaru.gitlab.io/images/lugaru-banner.png
      </image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://osslugaru.gitlab.io/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://gitlab.com/osslugaru/lugaru/issues</url>
  <url type="contact">https://webchat.freenode.net/#lugaru</url>
</component>

